Advertise your product or brand here contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
Anuncie su producto o marca aquם contבctenos www.OpenSubtitles.org hoy
English! I'm English!
¡Inglיs! ¡Soy inglיs!
It's grenadiers, mate.
Artilleros, amigo.
Make way!
¡Abran paso!
Out of the way!
¡Muיvanse!
Go, go, go!
¡Adelante!
Along the mole. All the way.
Por el muelle. Hasta el fondo.
The ship's about to leave.
El barco va a zarpar.
Where's the bloody air force?
¿Dףnde diablos estב la Fuerza Aיrea?
The navy's requisitioned her.
Lo requisף la Armada.
They've told us to strip her and load those life jackets.
Nos dijeron que lo vaciבramos y cargבramos esos salvavidas.
Some men across the Channel, at Dunkirk, need taking off.
Hay que rescatar unas tropas en Dunkerque, cruzando el Canal.
Some men?
¿Unas tropas?
Check fuel, Fortis 1 and 2.
Revisar combustible, Fortis 1 y 2.
70 gallons.
Tengo 320 litros.
68 gallons, Fortis Leader.
Yo 310 litros, Fortis Lםder.
Stay down at 500 feet to leave fuel
Mantיnganse a 150 metros para descargar.
for 40-minute fighting time over Dunkirk.
Tendrבn 40 minutos de lucha en Dunkerque.
Understood. Vector 128, angels point five.
Copiado. Vector 128, 150 metros de altura.
Save enough to get back.
Que les quede para volver.
No French soldiers. No French soldiers. No.
Soldados franceses no.
No, no French. English only. English only past this point.
No, franceses no. Sףlo ingleses. Sףlo ingleses a partir de aquם.
No. It's a British ship. No, you have your own ships.
No. Es un barco britבnico. No, ustedes tienen sus barcos.
Get back. Get back.
Atrבs.
No, you've got your own ships. This is a British ship.
Este es britבnico.
No, get back.
No, atrבs.
Look, get the stretchers through. There are stretchers coming.
Que pasen las camillas. Vienen las camillas.
Get out of the way! Out of the way!
¡Abran paso! ¡Muיvanse!
Go, go, go. Along the mole. All the way.
Adelante. Hasta el fondo del muelle.
The ship's about to leave. About to leave.
El barco va a zarpar. Estב por zarpar.
Along the mole. All the way.
Por el muelle. Hasta el fondo.
No.
No.
No, English only. English only!
No, sףlo ingleses. ¡Sףlo ingleses!
No!
¡No!
Ready on the stern!
¡Firmes en popa!
Yes, sir!
¡Sם, seסor!
Man the bowline!
¡A la bolina!
Any more room?
¿Hay mבs espacio?
You have to get back!
¡Tienen que retroceder!
That's two minutes.
Zarpa en dos minutos.
You've missed it. You've missed it.
Lo perdieron.
Is that the last one?
¿Es el תltimo?
Aye, sir.
Sם, seסor.
Break the line.
Suelten los amarres.
Come on! Come on!
¡Vamos!
Dunkirk's so far. Why can't they just load at Calais?
Dunkerque es muy lejos. ¿Por quי no cargan en Calais?
The enemy had something to say about it.
Parece que el enemigo no lo permite.
Ah, down here we're sitting ducks.
Aquם abajo somos blanco fבcil.
Keep 'em peeled. They'll come out of the sun.
Tengan los ojos abiertos. Saldrבn de la nada.
Up the line.
En la fila.
Oi. We'll take it.
Nosotros nos ocupamos.
Drop the gangplank!
¡Retiren la pasarela!
Yes, sir!
¡Sם, seסor!
Take a run at it.
Corre.
Ready on the stern line, George.
Suelta el cabo de popa, George.
Aren't you waiting on the navy?
¿No esperarבn a la armada?
They've asked for the Moonstone, they'll have her.
Ellos solicitaron el Moonstone y lo tendrבn.
And her captain.
Junto con su Capitבn.
Thanks for the help, George.
Gracias por la ayuda, George.
What are you doing?
¿Quי haces?
You do know where we're going?
Sabes adףnde vamos.
France.
A Francia.
Into war, George.
A la guerra, George.
I'll be useful, sir.
Los ayudarי, seסor.
Bandit, 11 o'clock.
Enemigo, a las 11:00 en punto.
Break.
Rompan filas.
He's on me.
Me sigue.
I'm on him.
Lo tengo.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight...
Uno, dos, tres, cuatro, cinco, seis, siete, ocho...
Oi, you two.
Ustedes dos.
Get a shift on.
Apתrense.
Yeah, pull him tight. Tie a knot in it.
Sם, tira fuerte. Hazle un nudo.
Back up the line. Both of you.
Bajen del barco. Los dos.
Off you go.
Fuera.
Off you go!
¡Fuera!
That last barrage has damaged the rudder.
El תltimo bombardeo daסף el timףn.
Uh, okay...
Bien...
Mr. Dawson!
¡Sr. Dawson!
One of ours, George.
Es de los nuestros, George.
On my mark, Fortis 2. Draw him left.
Lo tengo en la mira. Llיvalo a la izquierda.
Three, two, one.
Tres, dos, uno.
Mark.
Apunta.
Clear.
Listo.
Yeah, he's down for the count.
Sם, lo bajamos.
Fortis Leader, one bandit down.
Fortis Lםder, un enemigo menos.
Fortis Leader, do you read?
Fortis Lםder, ¿me copia?
Fortis 2, I have you to my port. I have no eyes on Fortis Leader. Over.
Fortis 2, a babor. No diviso a Fortis Lםder. Cambio.
Understood, Fortis 1.
Copiado, Fortis 1.
Orbit for a look.
Giremos para buscar.
How long, Lieutenant?
¿Cuבnto, Teniente?
We need to run a new cable, sir. They're scrambling.
Debemos mandar otro cable, seסor. Hacen interferencia.
Very well.
Muy bien.
Colonel, you're gonna have to decide how many more wounded to evacuate.
Coronel, tendrב que decidir cuבntos heridos mבs evacuaremos.
One stretcher takes the space of seven standing men.
Una camilla ocupa lo mismo que siete hombres de pie.
Excuse me.
Permiso.
- Rear Admiral. - Commander.
Contralmirante. Comandante.
How's the perimeter?
¿Cףmo estב el perםmetro?
Shrinking every day.
Cada vez mבs pequeסo.
But between our rear guard and the French, we're holding the line.
Pero mantenemos la posiciףn entre la retaguardia y los franceses.
And the enemy tanks have stopped.
Y los tanques enemigos se han detenido.
Why have they stopped?
¿Por quי?
when they can pick us off from the air, like fish in a barrel?
...si pueden aniquilarnos desde el aire?
How long does London expect the army
¿Cuבnto esperan en Londres que resistamos antes de negociar?
Make terms?
¿Negociar?
They're not stopping here. We need to get our army back.
Esto no serב todo. Debemos rescatar a nuestras tropas.
Britain's next and then the rest of the world.
Lo prףximo serב Gran Bretaסa, y luego el resto del mundo.
Christ.
¡Por Dios!
I mean, you can practically see it from here.
Casi se puede ver desde aquם.
What?
¿Quי cosa?
Home.
Nuestro hogar.
What about the French?
¿Quי hay de los franceses?
Arm in arm, leaving together.
Codo a codo, nos retiraremos juntos.
And privately?
¿Quי dijo en privado?
We need our army back.
Debemos rescatar a nuestros soldados.
How many men are they talking about, sir?
¿De cuבntos hombres estamos hablando, seסor?
Churchill wants 30,000. Ramsay's hoping we can give him 45.
Churchill quiere 30.000. Ramsay espera que lleguemos a 45.000.
There are 400,000 men on this beach, sir.
Hay 400.000 hombres en esta playa, seסor.
We'll just have to do our best.
Tendremos que hacer lo mejor que podamos.
Right, well, this mole stays open at all costs.
Pues este muelle quedarב abierto cueste lo que cueste.
We're in artillery range from the west. If anything else sinks here,
Estamos al alcance de la artillerםa. Si llega a hundirse algo mבs,
the mole's blocked and we're stuffed.
bloquearב el muelle, y nos dejarב sin salida.
Can't we load from the beaches?
¿No podemos cargar en la playa?
Better than standing out here when the dive bombs come.
Mejor que aquם, cuando lancen las bombas.
- It's impossible. - Too shallow?
- Es imposible. - ¿No hay profundidad?
'Cause anything that drafts over three feet can't get near.
Cualquier calado de mבs de un metro no llegarםa.
We don't have enough small boats to ferry men to the destroyers.
Y no alcanzan los botes para llevar a todos a los destructores.
Hey!
¡Oye!
Hey! Can you swim it?
¡Oye! ¿Llegas nadando?
Dad, can you get closer?
Papב, ¿puedes acercarte?
Can't risk it!
¡Es peligroso!
Hang on.
Espera.
What's your name?
¿Cףmo te llamas?
Wreckage below.
Abajo veo restos.
Is it more of the 109?
¿Es el mismo 109?
No.
No.
It's Fortis Leader. Over.
Es Fortis Lםder. Cambio.
You think he got out?
¿Habrב logrado escapar?
I didn't see a 'chute.
No vi el paracaםdas.
Record his position.
Registra su posiciףn.
Then set heading 128,
Y luego avanza al Vector 128,
height 1,000. Over.
a 300 metros. Cambio.
Vector 128, angels one. Understood.
Vector 128, 300 metros. Copiado.
Fortis 2, what's your fuel?
Fortis 2, ¿combustible?
50 gallons. Over.
Tengo 230 litros. Cambio.
50 gallons.
Doscientos treinta litros.
All right, keep letting me know.
De acuerdo. Sigue informבndome.
My gauge took a bit of a knock back there.
Mi indicador quedף un poco averiado.
Shouldn't you turn back?
¿No deberםas volver?
No, no.
No.
I'm fairly confident it's just the gauge.
Estoy seguro de que es sףlo el indicador.
- She's going down! - Cut her loose!
¡Estב hundiיndose!
What about the wounded?
¿Y los heridos?
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
¡Evacתen la nave!
Cut her loose, and push her off!
¡Suelten cabos y alיjenla!
We can't let her sink at the mole!
¡No puede hundirse en el muelle!
Push the bloody boat off!
¡Alejen ese maldito barco!
Help us!
¡Ayתdennos!
Do you want to come below?
¿Quieres venir abajo?
It's much warmer.
No hace tanto frםo.
It's out of the wind.
No llega el viento.
Here you go.
Toma.
Leave him be, George.
Dיjalo, George.
He feels safer on deck.
Se siente mבs seguro en la cubierta.
You would too if you'd been bombed.
Te pasarםa si te hubieran bombardeado.
U-boat.
Un submarino.
It was a U-boat.
Fue un submarino.
Get him some more tea, George.
Trבele mבs tי, George.
Right, we're about five minutes out,
Bien, estamos a cinco minutos,
so climb to 2,000. Over.
asם que sube a 600. Cambio.
That's more fuel.
Es mבs combustible.
I know, but I don't want to get jumped again.
Sם, pero no quiero que nos sorprendan.
Let's get a decent altitude.
Si subimos bastante, podremos atacar a los bastardos desde arriba.
Understood. Angels two.
Copiado. 600 metros.
Over.
Cambio.
Right, Highlanders.
Muy bien, soldados.
Let's find you another ship.
Busquemos otro barco para ustedes.
Come on.
Vamos.
Everyone else, keep climbing. Climb on the deck.
Los demבs sigan avanzando. A la cubierta.
Climb on the deck.
Avancen a la cubierta.
Watch your heads on the rail. Watch it.
Cuidado con la cabeza.
That's right, keep going down. Take a blanket.
Muy bien, sigan avanzando. Tomen una manta.
Down you go. Put this on, my love.
Ahם va. Ponte esto, querido.
Down you go. Keep going down.
Vamos. Sigan avanzando.
There's a nice cup of tea for you down there.
Allם los espera una taza de tי caliente.
Keep moving down.
Sigan avanzando.
Take a blanket.
Tomen una manta.
Try and make some room.
Hagan espacio.
Keep moving down, boys.
Sigan avanzando, muchachos.
This way.
Por aquם.
A cup of tea down there.
Una taza de tי los espera.
There you go. Down there. Move down there.
Ahם estב. Avancen. Sigan avanzando.
What's wrong with your friend?
¿Quי le pasa a tu amigo?
He's looking for a quick way out.
Busca una salida rבpida.
In case we go down.
Por si nos bombardean.
Where are we going?
¿Adףnde vamos?
Dunkirk.
A Dunkerque.
No, uh, no, no, we're going to England.
No, a Inglaterra.
We have to go to Dunkirk first.
Primero tenemos que ¡r a Dunkerque.
Look, I'm not going back.
No pienso volver.
Look at it.
Mira eso.
If we go there, we'll die.
Si vamos, moriremos todos.
I see your point, son.
Te entiendo, hijo.
Well, let's plot a course.
Tracemos el rumbo.
You can take your tea below and warm up.
Baja a tomar un tי y entrar en calor.
Peter, have we got space for a man to lie down?
Peter, ¿hay espacio para un hombre acostado?
Here, come on.
Adelante, vamos.
Just in there.
Por ahם.
I'll get you some more tea.
Te traigo mבs tי.
Is he a coward, Mr. Dawson?
¿ֹl es un cobarde, Sr. Dawson?
He's shell-shocked, George.
Estב conmocionado, George.
He's not himself.
No estב en sus cabales.
He may never be himself again.
Tal vez nunca vuelva a estarlo.
Here you are.
Toma.
40 gallons, Fortis 1.
Ciento ochenta litros, Fortis 1.
40 gallons, understood.
Ciento ochenta litros, bien.
Heinkel, 11 o'clock.
Un Heinkel a las 11:00 en punto.
She's lining up to drop her load on that minesweeper.
Estב preparבndose para bombardear a ese buscaminas.
Fighters?
¿Cazas?
Yeah, 109s off her starboard.
Sם, varios 109 a estribor.
I'm on the bomber.
Yo sigo al bombardero.
Got him! Got him!
¡Lo tengo!
Oh, she's turning. You must've damaged her.
Estב inclinבndose. Seguro le diste.
Where's the escort?
¿Y la escolta?
Well, I got one of...
Tengo a un...
I'm going down.
Estoy cayendo.
I'm on him. Bail out.
Lo tengo. Salta.
No, the swell looks good. I'm ditching.
No hay muchas olas. Bajarי el aviףn.
Don't leave us!
¡No nos dejen!
Come back!
¡Regresen!
- Wait for us! - Help! Help us!
- ¡Esperen! - ¡Ayתdennos!
Pick us up! Pick us up!
¡Llיvennos!
Come back!
¡Regresen!
Torpedo!
¡Un torpedo!
Abandon ship! Abandon ship!
¡Evacתen el barco!
Help!
¡Auxilio!
Get us out of here!
¡Sבquennos de aquם!
Spitfires, George.
Son Spitfire, George.
Greatest plane ever built.
Los mejores aviones de la historia.
You didn't even look.
Ni siquiera los vio.
Rolls-Royce Merlin engines.
Tienen motor Rolls-Royce Merlin.
Sweetest sound you could hear out here.
El sonido mבs hermoso que hay.
Hello?
¿Hola?
Could you open the door?
¿Podrםas abrir la puerta?
Hello? Can you hear me?
¿Hola? ¿Me oyes?
Open the door!
¡Abre la puerta!
Do you hear me?
¿Me oyes?
He wants to come out.
Quiere salir.
What have you done? Locked him in?
¿Quי hiciste? ¿Lo encerraste?
Let him out, for God's sake.
Dיjalo salir, por el amor de Dios.
Hello?
¿Hola?
Let me out!
¡Dיjame salir!
No. We have a job to do.
No. Tenemos una misiףn.
You're weekend sailors, not the bloody navy.
Y ustedes son marineros de fin de semana, no son de la Armada.
A man your age?
¿Un hombre de tu edad?
Men my age dictate this war.
Los hombres de mi edad manejan esta guerra.
Why should we be allowed to send our children to fight it?
¿Por quי tienen que salir a pelearla nuestros hijos?
You should be at home!
¡Vuelve a nuestro hogar!
Well, there won't be any home if we
Si permitimos una masacre del otro lado...
allow a slaughter across the Channel.
...del Canal, nos quedaremos sin hogar.
He's turning tail. I'm gonna get after him.
Estב en retirada. Lo voy a perseguir.
Good luck.
Buena suerte.
Watch your fuel. You're at 15 gallons.
Cuida el combustible. Tienes 70 litros.
15 gallons, understood.
Setenta litros, copiado.
Best of luck, Collins.
Mucha suerte, Collins.
Collins, do you read?
Collins, ¿me copias?
Oi! No! No!
¡No!
Get off! Get off!
¡Fuera!
Piss off, the both of you. It's too crowded.
Vבyanse los dos. Hay demasiada gente.
You can't leave us!
¡No pueden dejarnos!
Make some room!
¡Hagan espacio!
No!
¡No!
No! Get off!
¡No! ¡Fuera!
You men, leave off. You'll capsize the boat.
Vבyanse. Van a voltear el bote.
She's gone over twice on the way out here.
En el camino se dio vuelta dos veces.
You have to stay calm. There are plenty of boats.
Mantengan la calma. Hay suficientes botes.
Calm?
¿La calma?
Wait till you get torpedoed, then tell us to be calm!
Cuando recibas un torpedo, ¡dinos que nos calmemos!
You have life jackets?
¿Tienen chalecos salvavidas?
Yes, they do.
Sם.
Don't panic, boys. The water's not too rough
No entren en pבnico. El agua no estב agitada...
or too cold.
...ni muy frםa.
We're heading back to the beach.
Volveremos a la playa.
- Let's go to Dover! - Yeah!
- ¡Vamos a Dover! - ¡Sם!
We can't make it across the Channel in this, lads.
No podremos cruzar el Canal en este bote.
We need to get back to the beach and wait for another ride.
Debemos volver a la playa y esperar un barco.
You men in the water, float here, save your strength.
Los que estבn en el agua, quיdense flotando y no gasten fuerzas.
We'll come back for you.
Volveremos a buscarlos.
Oars in!
¡Remen!
Together, pull!
Juntos, ¡remen!
There's no hiding from this, son.
No hay escapatoria, hijo.
What is it you think you can do out there, on this thing?
¿Quי crees que puedes lograr con este barco?
There's not just us. A call went out.
No estamos solos. Hubo un llamado.
We aren't the only ones to answer, you know.
No somos los תnicos que respondimos.
You don't even have guns.
Ni siquiera tienes armas.
Do you have a gun?
¿Tת tienes un arma?
Yes, of course. A rifle, a 303.
Sם, claro, un rifle 303.
Did it help you against the dive bombers and the U-boats?
¿Te sirviף contra las bombas y los submarinos alemanes?
You're an old fool.
Eres un viejo necio.
I'm not going back.
Yo no voy a volver.
Turn it around.
Da la vuelta.
I'm not turning round.
No voy a dar la vuelta.
Turn it around!
¡Da la vuelta!
Turn it...
¡Dala!
- Calm it down, mate. - Turn it around!
- Cבlmate. - ¡Da la vuelta!
Wait, wait!
¡Espera!
Calm it down, mate.
Cבlmate.
George?
¿George?
George!
¡George!
What have you done?
¿Quי hiciste?
Okay, you're all right, George.
Estבs bien, George.
You're all right.
Estבs bien.
Hang on. Okay. Okay, just...
Resiste. Bien. Sףlo...
That's it. That's good enough.
Eso es. Bien.
It's gonna keep some pressure on. There we go.
Hay que mantenerlo presionado. Eso es.
Can you hear me, George?
¿Me oyes, George?
Come on, lads!
¡Vamos, muchachos!
Come on! Come on, boys!
¡Vamos!
It's a pier.
Es un espigףn.
For when the water comes in.
Para cuando suba la marea.
The tide's turning now.
Estב cambiando la marea.
How can you tell?
¿Cףmo sabes?
The bodies come back.
Vuelven los cadבveres.
Hey.
Oigan.
Hey, Highlanders!
¡Oigan, soldados!
What's that way?
¿Quי hay por allם?
A boat.
Un barco.
She's grounded.
Estב encallado.
Not when the tide comes in, she's not.
Cuando suba la marea, ya no lo estarב.
You and Mr. Dawson?
¿Tת y el Sr. Dawson?
It's the best thing I've ever done.
Es lo mejor que hice en mi vida.
You're all right. You're okay.
Estבs bien. No pasa nada.
Sea Cadet. It's the only thing I've ever done.
Fui cadete marino, lo תnico que hice.
It's all right. It's okay. Just have some water.
Estב bien. No pasa nada. Bebe un poco de agua.
I told my dad...
Le dije a mi papב...
I've done nothing at school
...que no hice nada en la escuela,
and that I would do something one day.
pero algתn dםa iba a hacer algo.
Maybe get in the local paper.
Tal vez salir en el diario del pueblo.
Maybe my teachers would see it.
Tal vez mis maestros lo verםan.
Okay, get some rest.
Bueno, descansa.
I can't.
No puedo.
What?
¿Quי?
I can't see.
No veo.
Sir.
Seסor.
The French have been forced back on the western side.
Los franceses debieron retroceder en el frente occidental.
They're still holding a perimeter?
Pero, ¿se mantiene el perםmetro?
For now.
Por ahora.
Officer coming through. Move yourselves. Move yourselves!
Abran paso que viene un Oficial. ¡Abran paso!
One?
¿Uno?
After yesterday's losses, it's one ship on the mole at a time.
Tras la pיrdida de ayer, podemos recibir un barco por vez.
The battle is here.
La batalla es aquם.
What the hell are they saving them for?
¿Para quי diablos guardan los barcos?
The next battle.
Para la prףxima batalla.
The one for Britain.
La que habrב en Gran Bretaסa.
It's the same with the planes.
Con los aviones hacen lo mismo.
But it's right there.
Pero es allם.
You can practically...
Casi se puede...
Seeing home doesn't help us get there, Colonel.
Ver nuestro hogar no nos ayudarב a llegar, Coronel.
They need to send more ships.
Tienen que mandar mבs barcos.
Every hour the enemy pushes closer.
El enemigo se acerca hora a hora.
They've activated the small vessels pool.
Han activado la base de embarcaciones pequeסas.
Small vessels?
¿Embarcaciones pequeסas?
It's the list of civilian boats for requisition.
La lista de barcos civiles para requisar.
Civilian?
¿Civiles?
We need destroyers.
Necesitamos destructores.
Small boats can load from the beach.
Las embarcaciones pequeסas llegan a la playa.
Not in these conditions.
En estas condiciones, no.
Well, I'd rather face waves than dive bombers.
Prefiero las olas que los bombarderos.
No, you're right. They won't get up in this.
No, es cierto. No subirבn a esto.
The Royal Engineers are building piers from lorries.
El Cuerpo de Ingenieros hace embarcaderos con camiones.
At least that should help us when the tide comes back.
Eso nos ayudarב cuando vuelva la marea.
Well, we'll know in six hours' time.
Lo sabremos en seis horas.
I thought the tides were every three?
Creם que cambiaba cada tres horas.
Then it's good that you're army and I'm navy, isn't it?
Menos mal que yo soy de la Armada y tת del Ejיrcito, entonces.
There. Vanquisher.
Ahם estב. El Vanquisher.
Where's the crew?
¿Dףnde estב la tripulaciףn?
Probably got spooked after they ran aground.
Se deben haber asustado al encallar.
Scarpered up the beach.
Seguro huyeron por la playa.
Why?
¿Por quי?
'Cause we're outside the perimeter. Enemy could be right there.
Porque estamos fuera del perםmetro. El enemigo podrםa estar ahם.
All right, best shut ourselves inside, boys.
Bien, mejor nos encerramos, entonces.
Wait for the high tide.
A esperar que suba la marea.
How long's that?
¿Cuבnto tarda?
Every three hours.
Tres horas.
I've put a bit of pressure on it.
Apliquי un poco de presiףn.
Strapped him up, made him comfortable.
Lo amarrי, para que estי mבs cףmodo.
What?
¿Quי?
It's bad, Dad.
Es grave, papב.
Well, should we turn back?
Bueno, ¿regresamos?
We've come so far.
Ya casi llegamos.
Dad, is that one of ours?
Papב, ¿ese es uno de los nuestros?
That's a Heinkel. They'll go for that minesweeper there.
Es un Heinkel. Atacarב a ese buscaminas de allם.
Hang on. Shouldn't we stand by to pick up survivors?
¿Esperamos para recoger sobrevivientes?
To do that we have to survive ourselves.
Para eso, debemos sobrevivir nosotros.
Poke your head out. See if the water's come in.
Asoma la cabeza. Fםjate si subiף la marea.
Talkative sod, aren't you?
Tת sם que eres conversador, ¿no?
It's barely come in at all.
Subiף muy poco.
- Fuck's sake. - Calm down.
- Carajo. - Cבlmate.
What goes out comes back in again, right?
Todo lo que baja, sube, ¿no?
Yeah, but how long?
Sם, pero ¿cuבnto tarda?
Spitfires!
¡Son Spitfire!
Come on.
Vamos.
Dad, he got him!
Papב, ¡le dio!
Yeah! Yeah!
¡Sם!
The Heinkel's moving off.
El Heinkel se va.
Yeah.
Sם.
Oh, no.
Ay, no.
Smoke from the Spitfire!
¡Sale humo del Spitfire!
Watch for a parachute!
¡Fםjate si cae el paracaםdas!
Oi.
Bueno.
Oi. Oi.
Sם.
Are you German?
¿Eres alemבn?
No, Dutch. Dutch!
No, holandיs. ¡Holandיs!
Merchant navy.
De la Marina Mercante.
Here to pick you up. To help you.
Vinimos a recogerlos. A ayudar.
Why'd you leave your boat?
¿Por quי abandonaron el barco?
In case the Germans come.
Por si venםan los alemanes.
We wait up the beach.
Esperamos en la playa.
You came back. The tide must be in.
Volviste. Debe haber subido la marea.
Coming. Coming, yes.
Sם, estב subiendo.
But more hours till we float.
Pero faltan horas para flotar.
Hours?
¿Horas?
Why'd you come back?
¿Por quי volviste?
Not so heavy when I left.
Cuando me fui, no habםa carga.
No 'chute!
¡No veo el paracaםdas!
Best of luck, Collins.
Mucha suerte, Collins.
Collins, do you read?
Collins, ¿me copias?
He's down.
Cayף.
Dad.
Papב.
Dad, watch the engine.
Papב, cuida el motor.
Dad, he's down. There was no 'chute.
Papב, cayף. No vi un paracaםdas.
Dad, come on. There was no 'chute.
Papב, vamos. No habםa paracaםdas.
He's probably dead.
Debe estar muerto.
Damn it, I hear you, Peter! I hear you!
¡Maldiciףn! ¡Ya te oם, Peter! ¡Te oם!
He may be alive. Maybe.
Tal vez estי vivo. Tal vez...
We may be able to help him.
Tal vez podamos ayudarlo.
No! Then they'll know we're in here.
¡No! Nos van a descubrir.
Why else are they shooting at us?
Si nos estבn disparando...
Look at the grouping.
Mira cףmo se agrupan.
Target practice.
Estבn practicando tiro.
Go. Plug it. Go, go.
Vamos. Tבpalo.
We have to plug it.
Tenemos que taparlo.
After you, mate.
Adelante, amigo.
You ready? Go!
¿Listo? ¡Vamos!
How do we get off? Do we need to ditch some ballast?
¿Cףmo hacemos? ¿Tenemos que descargar lastre?
Weight! Do we need to lose weight?
¡Peso! ¿Tenemos que perder peso?
Weight. Weight, yes.
Peso. Peso, sם.
Yes.
Sם.
Somebody needs to get off.
Tiene que bajar alguien.
Well volunteered.
Gracias por ofrecerte.
We don't need a volunteer.
No necesitamos que nadie se ofrezca.
I know someone who ought to get off.
Yo sי quiיn se tiene que bajar.
This one.
Este.
He's a German spy.
Es un espםa alemבn.
Don't be daft.
No seas ridםculo.
He's a fucking Jerry.
Es un alemבn de mierda.
Have you noticed he hasn't said a word?
¿No vieron que no dijo una palabra?
'Cause I have.
Porque yo sם.
He don't speak English.
No habla inglיs.
If he does it's with an accent that's thicker than sauerkraut sauce.
Y cuando habla, tiene un acento mבs alemבn que la salchicha.
You're daft. Tell him.
Estבs loco. Dile.
Yeah.
Sם.
Tell me.
Dime.
Tell me, Gibson.
Dime, Gibson.
Tell me!
¡Dime!
Tell him, for God's sake!
Dile, ¡por el amor de Dios!
A frog.
Un franchute.
A bloody frog.
Un maldito franchute.
A cowardly little queue-jumping frog.
Un franchute cobarde y tramposo.
Who's Gibson, eh?
¿Quiיn es Gibson?
Some naked, dead Englishman lying out on that sand?
¿Algתn inglיs que dejaste muerto y desnudo en la arena?
Did you at least have the decency to bury him?
¿Al menos tuviste la decencia de enterrarlo?
- Maybe he killed him. - He didn't kill him.
- Quizב lo matף יl. - No lo matף יl.
How do we know?
¿Cףmo sabemos?
How hard is it to find a dead Englishman on Dunkirk beach?
¿Tan difםcil te parece hallar un inglיs muerto en Dunkerque?
He didn't kill anyone.
ֹl no matף a nadie.
He was just looking for a way off the sand, like the rest of us.
Sףlo buscף el modo de irse de la playa, como todos.
Haven't they had enough practice by now?
¿No practicaron bastante ya?
They're trying to make sure she won't float.
Quieren asegurarse de que no vuelva a flotar.
Will she still float?
¿Y flotarב?
Float, yes. Yes, with less weight.
Sם, flotarב. Con menos peso.
And we know who's getting off.
Y ya sabemos quiיn bajarב.
No, you can't do that. He's French. He's on our side.
No puedes hacer eso. Es francיs, de nuestro bando.
Go on. Up you go.
Vamos. Arriba.
As soon as he pokes his head out, they'll slaughter him.
Cuando asome la cabeza, lo acribillarבn.
Better him than me.
Mejor que sea יl y no yo.
It's not fair.
No es justo.
Survival's not fair.
En la supervivencia no hay justicia.
No, it's shit.
No, sףlo hay mierda.
It's fear, and it's greed.
Hay miedo y egoםsmo.
Fate pushed through the bowels of men.
El destino que te pasa por las tripas.
Shit.
Mierda.
He saved our lives.
ֹl nos salvף la vida.
And he's about to do it again.
Y estב por salvarnos de nuevo.
No, don't! Stop!
¡No! ¡Para!
Somebody's gotta get off, so the rest of us can live.
Tiene que bajar alguno para que vivamos los demבs.
If you wanna volunteer...
Si quieres ofrecerte...
Fuck no.
Ni loco.
I'm going home.
Yo vuelvo a casa.
And if this is the price?
¿Y si el precio es este?
I'll live with it.
Lo pagarי.
But it's wrong.
Pero estב mal.
Go on!
¡Adelante!
One man's not going to make enough difference.
Uno sףlo no cambiarב las cosas.
You'd best hope it does, because you'd be volunteering next.
Mבs te vale que sם, porque si no, sigues tת.
What?
¿Quי?
We're regimental brothers, mate.
Somos hermanos de regimiento, amigo.
It's just the way it is.
Las cosas son asם.
We float!
¡Flotamos!
Start the bloody engine!
¡Arranca el maldito motor!
Afternoon.
Buenas tardes.
I'm sorry, son. I really don't know.
Lo siento, hijo. No sי, en serio.
You're right not moving him.
Haces bien en no moverlo.
You've done the best for him you can.
Has hecho lo mejor que puedes.
We've wasted the day.
Hemos perdido el dםa.
I share your frustration, Colonel.
Entiendo la frustraciףn, Coronel.
Johnny!
¡Johnny!
Grounded trawler, taking fire.
Pesquero encallado, recibiendo fuego.
They're breaking through the dunes to the east.
Estבn avanzando por las dunas al este.
This is it.
Se acabף.
Plug the holes!
¡Tapen los agujeros!
With what?
¿Con quי?
Other side! Other side!
¡Del otro lado!
What do you see?
¿Quי se ve?
Home.
Nuestro hogar.
Is he all right? The boy?
¿Estב bien el muchacho?
No.
No.
No, he's not.
No, estב mal.
Dad!
¡Papב!
Come on. Come on, Farrier. Come on.
Vamos, Farrier. Vamos.
There's men in the water!
¡Hay hombres en el agua!
Oil.
Es combustible.
It's oil. Oil. You're getting into oil!
¡Estבs flotando en combustible!
Keep coming.
Sigan viniendo.
Plenty of room.
Sobra espacio.
All right, below deck.
Bien, bajo la cubierta.
Abandon ship!
¡Evacתen el barco!
Gibson! Leave it!
¡Gibson! ¡Dיjalo!
Below decks.
Bajo cubierta.
before that oil catches fire.
...antes de que se incendie.
You go below decks or you get off my boat. That's your choice.
Si no vas bajo cubierta, te bajas de mi barco. Decide.
Keep coming.
Sigan.
He's dead, mate.
Estב muerto, amigo.
So be bloody careful with him.
Entonces trבtalo con cuidado.
Um, will he be okay?
¿Va a recuperarse?
The boy?
¿El muchacho?
Yeah.
Sם.
He's coming back round.
Estב dando la vuelta.
He's coming back round!
¡Estב dando la vuelta!
Come on, Farrier. Come on.
Vamos, Farrier. Vamos.
Get off the ship!
¡Baja del barco!
Come on, Farrier. Get around them.
Vamos, Farrier. Evבdelos.
Come on, come on.
Vamos.
Go.
Adelante.
Go! Go! Go!
¡Adelante!
Easy.
Tranquilo.
Take me home.
Llיvame a casa.
Where are you from?
¿De dףnde eres?
Out of Dartmouth!
¡De Dartmouth!
Christ.
Cielos.
You from Deal?
¿Tת eres de Deal?
I am!
¡Sם!
You watch the current at the mouth!
¡Cuidado con la corriente en la desembocadura!
Aye.
Sם.
And thank you!
¡Y gracias!
That's a fighter.
Es un caza.
Yes, an Me 109.
Sם, un Me 109.
From the south. Peter, you take the tiller.
Del sur. Peter, maneja el timףn.
Listen for my instructions.
Sigue mis instrucciones.
Point her south!
¡Apunta al sur!
Full speed, Peter.
A toda velocidad, Peter.
Keep coming round.
Sigue asם.
Before he fires, he's gotta drop his nose. I'll give you the signal.
Antes de atacar, debe bajar la trompa. Yo te avisarי.
- Now? - No, no. Wait.
- ¿Ahora? - No, espera.
Wait for him to commit to his line.
Espera que inicie su trayectoria.
Now!
¡Ahora!
He's gone.
Se fue.
Yeah, bigger fish to fry.
Sם, va a buscar peces mבs gordos.
How'd you know that stuff, anyway?
¿Cףmo supiste todo eso?
My son's one of you lot.
Mi hijo es uno de ustedes.
I knew he'd see us through.
Sabםa que nos iba a salvar.
You're RAF?
¿Eres de la Fuerza Aיrea?
No. Not me.
No. Yo no.
My brother. He flew Hurricanes.
Mi hermano. Piloteaba Hurricanes.
Died third week into the war.
Muriף a las tres semanas.
No, stay downstairs, please.
No, quיdense abajo, por favor.
We just wanna see the cliffs.
Sףlo queremos verlos riscos.
- Is it Dover? - No.
¿Eso es Dover?
That's Dorset.
Es Dorset.
But it's home.
Pero es nuestro hogar.
We let you all down, didn't we?
Los decepcionamos, ¿verdad?
Christ, how many you got in there?
Cielos, ¿cuבntos traen ahם?
Make your way to the trains.
Avancen hasta los trenes.
Where the hell were you?
¿Dףnde diablos estabas?
They know where you were.
Ellos saben dףnde estabas.
Bye.
Adiףs.
Cup of tea?
¿Un poco de tי?
Well done. Well done.
Felicitaciones.
Well done, lads.
Felicitaciones, muchachos.
All we did is survive.
Lo תnico que hicimos fue sobrevivir.
That's enough.
Es suficiente.
Well done.
Felicitaciones.
That old bloke wouldn't even look us in the eye.
Ese viejo ni siquiera nos miraba a los ojos.
Come on, private!
¡Vamos, soldado!
I know we're officers, but it's us or the enemy.
Sי que somos Oficiales, pero la alternativa es el enemigo.
So now is not the time to be particular.
No es momento de ponerse quisquilloso.
Well, Churchill got his 30,000.
Churchill recuperף sus 30.000.
And then some.
Y algunos mבs.
Almost 300,000.
Casi 300.000.
So far.
Por ahora.
So far?
¿Por ahora?
I'm staying.
Me voy a quedar.
For the French.
Por los franceses.
Hey!
¡Oye!
Where are we?
¿Dףnde estamos?
Siding. You'll be pulling in in a minute.
En el apartadero. Llegarבn en un minuto.
What station?
¿A quי estaciףn?
Woking.
Woking.
Grab me one of them papers.
Pבsame uno de esos diarios.
Go on!
¡Adelante!
Can't bear it.
No lo resisto.
You read it.
Lיelo tת.
Can't bear it?
¿No lo resistes?
They'll be spitting at us in the streets.
Nos escupirבn por las calles.
If they're not locked up waiting for the invasion.
Si no estבn encerrados esperando una invasiףn.
"Wars are not won by evacuations."
"Las guerras no se ganan evacuando".
I can't look.
No puedo mirar.
"But there was a victory inside this deliverance,"
"Pero hubo un triunfo en este rescate...
which should be noted."
"... que debe ser mencionado.
"Our thankfulness at the escape of our army"
"El alivio por el rescate de nuestro ejיrcito...
must not blind us to the fact that what has happened
"... no debe impedir que veamos que lo sucedido...
in France and Belgium is a colossal military disaster.
"... en Francia y Bיlgica es un desastre militar descomunal.
We must expect another blow to be struck almost immediately.
"Debemos estar preparados para otro golpe casi de inmediato.
We shall go on to the end.
"Seguiremos hasta el final.
We shall fight in France.
"Pelearemos en Francia.
We shall fight on the seas and oceans.
"Pelearemos en los mares y ocיanos".
We shall fight with growing confidence and growing strength in the air.
"Pelearemos en el aire cada vez con mבs confianza y fuerza.
We shall defend our island whatever the cost..."
"Defenderemos nuestra Isla cueste"...
What?
¿Quי?
"We shall defend our island whatever the cost may be.
"Defenderemos nuestra Isla, cueste lo que cueste.
We shall fight on the beaches.
"Pelearemos en las playas.
We shall fight on the landing grounds.
"Pelearemos en las pistas.
We shall fight in the fields and in the streets.
"Pelearemos en el campo y en la calle.
We shall fight in the hills.
"Pelearemos en la montaסa.
We shall never surrender.
"Nunca nos rendiremos.
And even if this island or a large part of it
"Y aunque esta Isla, toda o en gran parte,
then our Empire beyond the seas, armed and guarded by the British Fleet,
"nuestro Imperio en ultramar,
would carry on the struggle
"continuarםa peleando...
until, in God's good time,
"... hasta que, Dios quiera,
the New World, with all its power and might,
"el Nuevo Mundo, con todo su poder y su fuerza,
steps forth to the rescue and the liberation of the old."
"de un paso al frente para rescatar y liberar al Viejo Mundo".